<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Core Reflections</title>
    <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Core Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:08:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://corereflections.org.uk/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Development</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/community-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:08:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/community-development/</guid>
      <description>Community Development Community Development is a powerful tool to support and work with local groups of people to effect social change. For example when crisis/ issues has affected or impacted on their lives, and their community in some way. By encouraging people to actively take part in a group and to work together they can feel empowered; they will find a shared voice and feel they are being listened to, and importantly that their opinions matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coaching</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:08:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/coaching/</guid>
      <description>Coaching People seeking coaching are usually Managers, Directors, CEOs or Team leaders. Although this can be expanded to other management positions.
This usually takes place between two people the Coach and the professional, who has requested support with their work/ organisation/ staff member/team etc.
The Coach’s role is to enable the professional to be listened too, and allow discussion to take place , in some instances the Coach may observe a situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediation</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/mediation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:07:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/mediation/</guid>
      <description>Mediation A Mediator is required to assist a specific situation around conflict in the work place. This may occur when someone raises a complaint, or concerns about the way they feel they are being treated for example by a work colleagues, or a Line manager, or there may be a culture clash such as a dispute between staff members, or harassment and bullying or an organisation change that requires mediation to help that change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflective Practice</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/reflective-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:07:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/reflective-practice/</guid>
      <description>Reflective Practice Reflective Practice offers a wide range of staff groups/managers the opportunity to take time out of a busy pressurised working week to be able to think and reflect about the work they do, and their role. Different staff groups will have different needs; thus, the initial meeting will determine what these needs are. Staff groups come from a range of professions, which include health, social care, Voluntary sector, Local Authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staff Groups</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/staff-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:07:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/staff-groups/</guid>
      <description>Staff Groups Staff Bereavement Groups During the Coronavirus pandemic, there has been few families, friends, colleagues that have not been affected. Especially at a time when front line staff, within the NHS, Local Authority, and Teaching profession have felt an enormous pressure to be resilient. Everyone within these groups are under enormous pressure to continue to perform at the highest of standard, at one of the most unprecedent time that we have seen as a country, world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Supervision</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/clinical-supervision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:06:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/clinical-supervision/</guid>
      <description>Clinical Supervision Clinical Supervision is offered to professional practitioners. This supports and underpins clinical work and development. It enhances the practitioner’s knowledge by discussing clinical material/ or staffing issues. This is usually when the practitioner brings a Clinical case or /Staffing issue to supervision to discuss and think about in more detail. This could usually entail a range of issues such as Safeguarding, Risk management, Staffing concerns, as well as Clinical client case material and the personal impact the client/staff member is having upon them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counselling</title>
      <link>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/counselling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:05:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corereflections.org.uk/services/counselling/</guid>
      <description>Counselling Counselling is known as talking therapy or signing therapy if you are a Deaf/BSL user. It is face to face therapy delivered in a secure trusting relationship between Counsellor and client in a safe environment.
People will often seek therapy for different reasons some examples are when they are experiencing one or more of the following:
 Coping with a long-term health condition. End of life Trauma Bereavement Relationship issues Harassment and bullying issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>